<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Everyday Linux</title>
    <link>https://briantward.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Everyday Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="https://briantward.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>RHEL Port Forwarding Using Firewalld</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/rhel-port-forwarding.adoc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/rhel-port-forwarding.adoc/</guid>
        <description>RHEL Port Forwarding Using Firewalld Never underestimate the simplicity of a feature and the complications of a network.
 RHEL 7 uses firewalld, which has a very simple syntax for port forwarding across the incoming port of an external interface to a NATed IP on an internal device. No matter what I tried in variations from the base documentation I simply could not get it to work.
 In this configuration, note that I have eth0 on NetworkManager external zone with masquerade and eth1 on zone internal.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lenovo Intel i915 Video Drivers in Linux, Part 3</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video-part3/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video-part3/</guid>
        <description>Lenovo Intel i915 Video Drivers in Linux, Part 3 Problem Scenario/Steps: Lenovo T460s thinkpad ultra dock P/N SD20A06046 Type 40A2 S/N M3-A0AC8E 16/11+ fedora 26/27/28/29, according to my records any kernel since 4.15.9-300.fc27.x86_64
  Dock laptop in docking station with two connected monitors, one HDMI and one DVI.
  Undock laptop.
  Redock laptop → screen failure and system lock until undock again. Leave it long enough and it will reboot itself.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lenovo Intel i915 Video Drivers in Linux, Part 2</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video-part2/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video-part2/</guid>
        <description>Lenovo Intel i915 Video Drivers in Linux, Part 2 Problem Scenario/Steps: Lenovo T460s thinkpad ultra dock P/N SD20A06046 Type 40A2 S/N M3-A0AC8E 16/11+ fedora 26/27/28/29, according to my records any kernel since 4.15.9-300.fc27.x86_64
  Dock laptop in docking station with two connected monitors, one HDMI and one DVI.
  Undock laptop.
  Redock laptop → screen failure and system lock until undock again. Leave it long enough and it will reboot itself.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lenovo BIOS/UEFI update via USB from Linux</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-bios-update/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-bios-update/</guid>
        <description>I’m on a Lenovo T460s running fedora 27. One day, I ran into an issue with my video setup. It occurred to me that I had not updated my bios in a while, and since the whole Meltdown/Spectre thing came up, I should probably check on this. Yes, sure enough, I was on patch 1.20, the latest was 1.34, and the fix for Meltdown/Spectre was in 1.31. Good thing no one cares about my machine but me.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lenovo Intel i915 Video Drivers in Linux</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/lenovo-linux-intel-i915-video/</guid>
        <description>Note: Out of Date and incorrect analysis.
 I’m running fedora 27 on my Lenovo T460s and have been for a while. I have a docking station with two 24&amp;#34; monitors at work and another docking station with two 27&amp;#34; monitors at home. I switch between them frequently. Back in fedora 21 and 22 I had tons of problems. Sometimes monitors didn’t come on, sometimes one monitor came on, and sometimes things worked fine.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSH-Agent</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/ssh-agent/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/ssh-agent/</guid>
        <description>Every now and then for some reason my ssh-agent does work by default on startup. I have to reach out to this lovely stackoverflow to remember such a simple command:
 exec ssh-agent bash ssh-add ~/.ssh/*   alternatively
 eval `ssh-agent -s` ssh-add ~/.ssh/*   https://stackoverflow.com/questions/17846529/could-not-open-a-connection-to-your-authentication-agent
 </description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
