<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rhel on Everyday Linux</title>
    <link>https://briantward.github.io/categories/rhel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rhel on Everyday Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
      <atom:link href="https://briantward.github.io/categories/rhel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Running Secure Containers on Fedora 31 and RHEL 8</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/running-secure-containers-on-fedora/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/running-secure-containers-on-fedora/</guid>
        <description>Running Secure Containers on Fedora 31 and RHEL 8 The first thing to note here, is that &#34;secured&#34; means running the container with SELinux enforcing. If you don&amp;#8217;t care about SELinux or have other alternatives in place, move along here, as you won&amp;#8217;t find this useful. I will not be discussing application security or platform security.
 The second thing to note here, is that setting this up requires more work, per container, than running your container on OpenShift, which is Red Hat&amp;#8217;s Container platform built on Kubernetes.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expand a Qemu Disk</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/expand-qemu-disk/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/expand-qemu-disk/</guid>
        <description>Expand a Qemu Disk I exhausted the disk space on my Windows VM and found I needed more room. This is one of those lovely tasks that actually has simple and good documentation and works easily enough.
 I followed these instructions using qemu-resize:
 https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/7/html/virtualization_deployment_and_administration_guide/sect-using_qemu_img-re_sizing_the_disk_image
 But you might find this just as helpful:
 https://maunium.net/blog/resizing-qcow2-images/
 Here is another read on using virt-resize instead of qemu-resize but a little more to it:</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build A Router</title>
        <link>https://briantward.github.io/build-a-router/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://briantward.github.io/build-a-router/</guid>
        <description>Build A Router on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7 This provided a nice resource for reference.[1] I will elaborate a litte more here. I wanted to set up a custom router to the internet, to provide advanced firewall and logging features. Note that this example does not provide DHCP services. In my case, I have a secondary off-the-shelf (OTS) router doing that. Since the OTS router did not offer advanced firewall, NAT, port-forwarding, and such features, I decided to build my own.</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
